RODNEY TIPTON

Software Developer

CONTACT

- - +1 604-792-1930
 - Chilliwack, BC V2P 2M1
 - <u>LinkedI</u>n in
 - https://github.com/Techdev115

EDUCATION

Bachelor of information
Computer Science
Aston University
April 2012 - September 2016
Aston St, Birmingham B4 7ET, UK

SKILLS

JavaScript

React.js

Next.js

Node.js

Express.js

REST API/GraphQL

SQL (PostgreSQL, MySQL,

MongoDB)

Cloud (GCP, AWS)

Python

Typescript

HTML/ CSS

Material UI

CI/CD

SUMMARY

A seasoned software developer who loves building web application. With 5 years of professional work experience, I am a strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Computer Programming focused on Computer Science from the Aston University.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer

Wasobe Inc

September 2021 - July 2022 / Vancouver, BC

- Consulted CTO to deliver latest tech stacks and best industry practices.
- Modified React frontend infrastructure to improve performance & resolve potential issues.
- Improved web application rendering performance 10% faster.

Web Developer

Textual

November 2019 - June 2021 / New York, NY

- Modernized the innovative e-commerce platform by leading the frontend development team as a principle developer.
- Committed to SaaS platform development and maintenance project as a web developer.
- Delivered 100% functional SaaS platform to serveral companies and successfully signed contracts.

Web Developer

SESH, inc

May 2018 - April 2019 / Sydney

- Managed a team of 5 web developers to deliver web frontend/backend.
 Organized and launched the entire development process, supervised day -to-day progress of development works of team members.
- Built React web frontend & Node backend, hosted on AWS cloud.
 Developed live streaming & recording platform using wowza, customized litsl frontend, created WebRTC server in Node.
- Delivered platform to the client successfully in agreed timeline and acquired 100% client satisfaction.